rangle.io 2016-10-29

# Privacy Policy | Rangle.io

######  Privacy Policy 

#### Introduction

Rangle.io Inc. (here referred to as Rangle.io or "we") respects all individuals' preferences concerning the collection and use of their personal information ("data"). Our goal is to run several opt-in mailing lists and contests at events which will provide our mailing-list subscribers and our website visitors, and third party conference attendees ("users") with information they will find relevant. This policy statement is here to let you know how we collect data, why we collect it, and what choices you have concerning its use.

Please note that Rangle.io maintains the same privacy practices described in this policy for data we collect off-line; accordingly, references below to online subscribers also apply to individuals from whom we collect data off-line (for example, on mailing list sign-up forms circulated at conferences or local meetup events or through research for organizations who share our interests).

Rangle.io’s main office is located at: 82 Peter Street, 3rd floor. Toronto, Ontario Canada M5V 2G5

#### Data Collection Methods

Rangle.io collects data related to our users through the following methods:

  * The registration form for our online opt-in mailing through our main site: [http://rangle.io](http://rangle.io/) or a landing page, or contest entry page, that we host. We may also have distinct media, contests and other event-specific sign-up forms.
  * Cookies
  * Sign-up sheets which are circulated at events

#### Types of Information

The data collected may include the following information:

  * Subscribers' contact information (name, address, company, title, phone, fax, email, web, social media handles)
  * A selection of interests for future communications
  * The subscriber's choices as to why we may contact them
  * The subscriber’s work title, company, and industry they work in
  * The subscriber's IP address and geographic location

#### Consent

_How do you get my consent?_

When you provide us with personal information to sign-up for our e-newsletter list, or to enter your information to sign-up for one of our contests at an event, you’re implying that you consent to our collecting your information and using it for that specific reason only.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason, we will either ask you directly for your expressed consent, or provide you with an opportunity to say no. Users can read this Privacy Statement on our website, where we have included a link.

Users who opt in via a website's mailing list sign-up form will immediately be able to view a ‘Thank You’ page or inline ‘Thank You’ text, which indicates that their submission has been received.

_How do I withdraw my consent?_

If after you opt-in, you change your mind, you may withdraw your consent for us to contact you, for the continued collection, use or disclosure of your information, at anytime, by contacting us at [privacy@rangle.io](mailto:privacy@rangle.io) or mailing us at: Rangle.io Inc. 82 Peter St. Toronto Ontario Canada M5V 2G5

#### Disclosure

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law.

#### Hubspot

Our forms and online contest landing pages are hosted on HubSpot’s CMS and automated marketing platform. They provide us with the online contact management platform that allows us to create and share e-newsletters with you.

Your data is stored through HubSpot’s data storage, databases and the general HubSpot application. They store your data on a secure server behind a firewall.

#### Third-Party Links

Rangle.io and our portal websites includes links to non-Rangle.io sites we believe may be of interest to our visitors. These links are provided as a convenience, and the sites they point to are beyond our control. You are advised to check the privacy policies and terms of use of those sites before providing any personal data to them.

#### Cookies

**Definition**

A "cookie" is a small piece of information sent by a Web server to store on a Web browser so it can later be read back from that browser.

#### Purposes

We may set cookies for the following purposes:

  * To facilitate login or other site navigation procedures
  * To improve the functionality of the website by avoiding duplicate data entry, facilitating navigation, and increasing the relevance of content
  * To store user preferences and profile information used to personalize the content that is shown

We’ve included a link to the list of cookies we use below, so you that you can choose if you want to opt-out of cookies or not. View the cookies set by HubSpot when a user visits our site here: <http://help.hubspot.com/articles/KCS_Article/Reports/What-cookies-does-HubSpot-set-in-a-visitor-s-browser>

#### Use of data

Cookies on the site, and the associated data, will be used only for the purposes stated in Section 3 (How We Use The Data We Collect), below.

#### Opting out

While we do not offer an opt-out on the site for cookies, browsers provide you with information and control over cookies. You can set your Web browser to alert you when a cookie is being used. You can also get information on the duration of the cookie and what server your data is being returned to. You then have the opportunity to accept or reject the cookie. Additionally, you can set your browser to refuse all cookies or accept only cookies returned to the originating servers. Users can generally disable the cookie feature on their browser without affecting their ability to use the site, except in some cases where cookies are used as an essential security feature necessary for transaction completion.

#### How We Use The Data We Collect

Rangle.io collects data from users for the following purposes

  * Notifying users of information relevant to a particular webinar, blog post, or campaign is the primary purpose of our network.
  * Sending segmented e-newsletters to different lists for users interested in a particular offering from Rangle.io. This is another purpose of our sign-up forms.
  * Answering user inquiries. We will use subscribers' contact information to facilitate our handling of their registrations for newsletters and specific requests for further information.
  * Providing information on related resources. We may provide users with information on educational events, training, or relevant online content.

#### Preferences and Unsubscribing**

**Email Unsubscribe Links**

All emails sent by Rangle.io to our mailing lists will include a single-click "Unsubscribe" link, which will direct the user to a page where they can remove their data from our database.

#### Unsubscribe Support

We will also continuously provide support personnel ([privacy@rangle.io](mailto:privacy@rangle.io)) who will promptly remove any user from our lists upon request, with no questions asked. Users who are removed from our lists by staff will be notified of their removal.

#### If You are Experiencing Problems

Please contact us at [privacy@rangle.io](mailto:privacy@rangle.io) if you believe you have mistakenly received information after unsubscribing or if you would like to unsubscribe and have been unable to use the unsubscribe mechanisms provided.

#### Information-Sharing Policy

The mail list you have joined may have been off another site (other than Rangle.io) or a contest site that we host and maintain. Subscriber's personal data is handled by Rangle.io on behalf of the specific partner. Rangle.io will never sell the data to anyone under any circumstances. Nor will we share any detail of subscribers' personal data with any company, entity or individual, with the sole exception of the company who owns the portal website itself. Moreover, The Company's access to data applies solely to information originating off the website owned and operated by the company and is also bound by the terms under which the member subscribed. The Company is also not allowed to share or sell the data to any other party, The Company's rights remain restricted to usage determined by the members' choices as to what information they wish to receive, which they selected at the time they signed up.

For more information, contact: Rangle.io 82 Peter Street, 3rd floor Toronto, Ontario Canada M5V 2G5 [privacy@rangle.io](mailto:privacy@rangle.io)

#### Security

**General Statement**

Rangle.io is concerned with the security of the data we have collected and has in place reasonable measures to prevent unauthorized access to that information. These measures include policies, procedures, and technical elements relating to data access controls. In addition, Rangle.io uses standard online security protocols and mechanisms to exchange the transmission of sensitive data such as personal information, as well as requiring all staff and contractors to sign confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements if they will be in contact or have access to data.

#### Data Transfer

Our servers are located in Canada and data processing occurs primarily in Toronto, Ontario, Canada.

#### Security Breach Policy

In the event that individual personal data is acquired, or is reasonably believed to have been acquired, by an unauthorized person and applicable law requires notification, Rangle.io will notify the affected individual of the breach by email or, if Rangle.io is unable to contact the individual by email, then by mail. Notice will be given promptly, consistent with the legitimate needs of law enforcement and any measures necessary for Rangle.io or law enforcement to determine the scope of the breach and to assure or restore the integrity of the data system. Rangle.io may delay notification if Rangle.io or a law enforcement agency determines that the notification will impede a criminal investigation, unless and until Rangle.io or the agency determines that notification will not compromise the investigation.

#### Compliance Issues

Rangle.io privacy policy is designed to comply in full with all US and Canadian privacy laws. Should you believe your data has been used in a way that is not consistent with this policy or your stated preferences, or should you have further questions related to this policy, please contact Rangle.io by email at [privacy@rangle.io](mailto:privacy@rangle.io). Written inquiries may be addressed to: Rangle.io 82 Peter Street, 3rd floor. Toronto, Ontario Canada M5V 2G5 [privacy@rangle.io](mailto:privacy@rangle.io)

#### Changes to this privacy policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

If our store is acquired or merged with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners so that we may continue to sell products to you.

#### Questions and contact information

If you would like to: access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, register a complaint, or simply want more information contact our Privacy Compliance Officer at [privacy@rangle.io](mailto:privacy@rangle.io) or by mail at Rangle.io Inc.

[Re: Privacy Compliance Officer]

[82 Peter St. Toronto Ontario Canada M5V 2G5]
